Guide to the WHAM! (Women's Health Action and Mobilization) Records TAM.162
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
WHAM! (Women's Health Action and Mobilization) Records
Bulk, 1991-1995
1970-2010
TAM.162
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
31.75 linear feet in 32 boxes
Women's Health Action and Mobilization, or WHAM!, was founded in 1989 in response to the U.S. Supreme Court's decision in Webster vs. Reproductive Health Services of Missouri, which granted states more power to restrict women’s access to abortion. It was first a direct action committee of the Reproductive Rights Coalition until that larger group dissolved, and WHAM! became an independent organization. The collection reveals several important aspects of WHAM! as an organization. First, the collection reflects the decentralized and grassroots nature of WHAM! There was not a hierarchical leadership structure, and the role of record keeping fell to weekly facilitators, who rotated responsibilities. Detailed records ended up being kept by the individuals most involved in planning actions, a fact that reflects WHAM!'s practice of allowing any member to propose an action at a weekly meeting and form a working group to plan it. As a result, the collection contains documentation by several members, and does not contain a large quantity of traditional material, such as extensive minutes or official correspondence. Second, the collection reveals WHAM!'s connections with a variety of other organizations, particularly ACT UP and mainstream women's organizations, including Planned Parenthood, the National Abortion Rights Action League, and the National Organization for Women.
WHAM! (Women's Health Action and Mobilization).
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The bulk of the WHAM! Records were donated by Elizabeth Meixell in 1993, with additional deposits in 1998 and 2004. Additional records were donated by WHAM! members Tracy Morgan, Stacey Mink in 1994, Erica Blitz in 1995, Shannon Cain in 2004, Karen Ramspacher in 2004, and Neil De Mause and Mindy Nass in 2004.
In 2012, Marsha Clark made a donation of materials that comprise Boxes 27 and 28, as well as the buttons in Box 29. The accession number associated with this gift is 2012.079.
In 2014, Elizabeth Meixell made an additional donation of materials that comprise Boxes 29-32, as well as the "microbicides" banner in Box 28. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.012.
Arrangement
The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has largely been maintained, though materials in Boxes 1-4 may have been arranged chronologically or alphabetically within each document type by Tamiment archivists.
Each video and audio item in Box 5 has been assigned a unique number (i.e. WHAM A-01).
Access Restrictions
Permission of donor required. Please contact tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu
Scope and Content Note
The collection reveals several important aspects of WHAM as an organization. First, the collection reflects the decentralized and grassroots nature of WHAM! There was not a hierarchical leadership structure, and the role of record keeping fell to weekly facilitators, who rotated responsibilities. Detailed records ended up being kept by the individuals most involved in planning actions, a fact that reflects WHAM!'s practice of allowing any member to propose an action at a weekly meeting and form a working group to plan it. As a result, the collection contains documentation by several members, and does not contain a large quantity of traditional material, such as extensive minutes or official correspondence. Second, the collection reveals WHAM’s connections with a variety of other organizations, particularly ACT UP and mainstream women’s organizations, including Planned Parenthood, the National Abortion Rights Action League, and the National Organization for Women.
Correspondence in Box 1 contains examples of letters received by and written by WHAM! members, including letters of protest written to a variety of elected officials and companies, letters of inquiry from women across the country, and correspondence with other women’s organizations. The series also contains a limited number of internal documents in which members communicated with each other about issues facing the organization.
General files in Boxes 1-3 document the issues addressed by WHAM. The series covers both actions and campaigns organized by WHAM, such as the protests against the 1991 “Gag Rule” and their Tax the Church campaign against John Cardinal O’Connor, as well as the activities of several of its Working Groups. The series extensively covers WHAM’s Clinic Defense activities, both those conducted under the WHAM banner and those organized by the New York City Clinic Defense Task Force, a group that began as a WHAM committee.
Subject and research files in Box 3 contain clippings, articles, and other background material on issues of concern to WHAM members, particularly abortion and other women’s health issues.
Clippings in Box 4 contain xeroxed clippings collected by WHAM! members, about women's health-related issues as well as press coverage of WHAM.
Files on other organizations in Box 4 contain ephemera collected by WHAM! members about other organizations, particularly ACT UP, other women’s organizations, and anti-abortion groups.
Box 5 consists of audiovisual material. Some tapes document WHAM and ACT UP events and demonstrations, including an extensive series of video tapes of WHAM’s Resisting Racism workshops. Other materials include abortion-related news clips recorded by WHAM members, and answering machine tapes documenting incoming calls to WHAM. A few published videos related to women’s health and clinic defense are also included.
Historical/Biographical Note
Women's Health Action and Mobilization, or WHAM!, was founded in 1989 in response to the U.S. Supreme Court's decision in Webster vs. Reproductive Health Services of Missouri, which granted states more power to restrict women’s access to abortion. It was first a direct action committee of the Reproductive Rights Coalition until that larger group dissolved, and WHAM! became an independent organization. WHAM emerged, then, at a moment when abortion had exploded as one of the most prominent, controversial, and polarizing issues in American life, and many women felt that the Webster decision was emblematic of a larger, serious threat to the protections of the 1973 Roe v. Wade decision. Operation Rescue was shutting down women’s clinics, budget cuts in New York City threatened to close community family planning clinics, and Supreme Court decisions, including the 1991 "Gag" rule, were generating what WHAM felt to be a crisis in women’s health. While several national organizations -- like the National Organization for Women, the National Abortion Rights Action League and Planned Parenthood -- were doing abortions rights work on the legislative and legal fronts, WHAM felt that a stronger response was needed in light of increasingly organized and high-profile anti-abortion activism of the religious right. Drawing on the influence of the AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power (ACT UP), WHAM!'s focus was on direct action that specifically targeted officials and institutions who controlled public policy and programs, and it relied on the use of savvy graphics and media-centered actions, civil disobedience, and phone zaps. WHAM became known for its high-visibility, aggressive actions aimed at leaders and institutions that controlled policy around women’s health issues, including the Centers for Disease Control, the Catholic Church, the U.S. Supreme Court, and elected officials. While one of WHAM!'s primary goals was absolute access to abortion on demand, they hoped from the beginning to construe reproductive rights broadly, to include not only the prevention of conception and unwanted pregnancy, but also access to health care generally and the right to feed, clothe, and educate their families regardless of race, class, or sexual orientation. This broad set of concerns was reflected by one of WHAM’s early and most notorious actions, in conjunction with ACT UP: the Stop the Church demonstration at St. Patrick’s Cathderal in December, 1989, to protest John Cardinal O’Connor’s positions on abortion, AIDS, and homosexuality. Over 5,000 people demonstrated outside while protestors disrupted the homily inside the church. This joint demonstration, as activist and journalist Esther Kaplan wrote, “testified to the creative strength of a coalition built around sexual and reproductive freedom.” This action was emblematic of WHAM’s ongoing attacks on the Catholic Church, and as the song and chant sheets in the collection testify, they coined a number of slogans aimed at the church, including, "Pray, you’ll need it/ Your cause will be defeated," and "Four, Six, Eight, Ten/Why are all your leaders men?"
Over the years, in conjunction with other groups like the Bay Area Coalition Against Operation Rescue and the Washington Area Clinic Defense Task Force, WHAM developed a model set of practices for protecting access to women’s clinics targeted by anti-abortion groups. A WHAM committee, the New York Clinic Defense Task Force, eventually developed into a separate organization to focus solely on this ongoing, weekly task. Another key group that developed within WHAM’s clinic defense activities was the Church Ladies for Choice, a group of (mostly) gay men dressed in their finest church lady drag, replete with flower-print polyester frocks and sensible shoes who, in their words, "reverse the venom of anti-abortion terrorists with raucous safe sex fun," entertaining clinic defenders with reworked hymns and standards, including "This Womb is My Womb," "Every Sperm is Sacred," and "God is a Lesbian" to the tune of "My Country ‘Tis of Thee."
The core of WHAM’s activity revolved around high-visibility, aggressive direct actions, often conducted through a joint WHAM-ACT UP affinity group called Action Tours. WHAM joined with ACT UP and NOW to protest the nomination of David Souter to the U.S. Supreme Court, and one WHAM member, along with eleven ACT UP members, got national attention for their civil disobedience inside Congress. And in one of their most publicized actions, they “gagged” the Statue of Liberty to protest the so-called "gag rule" that prevented federally funded health clinics from counseling abortion. WHAM members dropped a banner that read "Abortion is Health Care/ Health Care is a Right" over the statue’s pedestal and obscured her face with another banner reading "No Choice/No Liberty." WHAM again joined with ACT UP to occupy the offices of the Centers for Disease Control in New York to demand that the official definition of AIDS be expanded to include infections specific to women and IV drug users. While the abortion debate raged across the country in the early nineties, it also sparked debate within the women’s movement. The constant attacks on clinics, and the ongoing legal battle over the definition of abortion put activists in what many felt was a narrowing, reactive position that threatened to drain energy from the movement over time. Many WHAM members wanted to adopt a more proactive approach to women’s health issues and to connect more effectively with the issues of race and class that shaped access to health care, but it was unclear if the organization could sustain wide-ranging work on a variety of issues when it had been most effective in honing techniques around public awareness and clinic defense. In response to criticisms that the group attracted primarily white activists, WHAM began conducting "Resisting Racism" workshops in 1992 and 1993.
Appraisal note
Duplicative materials were removed from the 2014 accession, as was an inflatable nun and a New York City t-shirt.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Due to the fragile nature of much of the original media, audiovisual material must have digital surrogates made before they can be used by researchers. Requests should be sent to tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu.
Meixell, Elizabeth; WHAM! (Women's Health Action and Mobilization).; Abortion |z United States.; Civil disobedience |z United States.; Direct action |z United States.; Feminism |z United States.; Feminists |z United States.; Reproductive rights |z United States.; Women |x Health and hygiene |z United States.
- Correspondence: Elizabeth Meixell, 1989-1994 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: WHAM, undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence: WHAM, 1989-1991 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: WHAM, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: WHAM, 1994 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: WHAM Internal, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
- 11th Hour Coalition, 1992 (Box 1)
- 19th Anniversary of Roe v. Wade, 1992 (Box 1)
- Action Tours (WHAM & ACT UP affinity group), 1991-1994 (Box 1)
- Baxandall, Rosalyn: Women and Abortion, 1992 (Box 1)
- Breast Cancer, 1989-1993 (Box 1)
- Buffalo Clinic Defense: Clippings, 1992 (Box 1)
- Buffalo United for Choice, 1992 (Box 1)
- Bush, President George: Zap Action, 1991 (Box 1)
- Centers for Disease Control: HIV/AIDS Protest, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
- Chant and Song Sheets, 1989-1991 (Box 1)
- Church Ladies for Choice, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
- Clinic Clients Survey, 1993 (Box 1)
- Clinic Defense, undated (Box 1)
- Clinic Defense, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
- Clinic Defense, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
- Clinic Defense: Clinic Listings, 1990-1992 (Box 1)
- Clinic Defense: Clinic Surveys, undated (Box 1)
- Clinic Defense: Phone Tree, undated (Box 1)
- Clinic Defense Training Materials, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
- Clinic Information, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
- Community Family Planning Council (CFPC) Budget Cuts, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
- Covenant House Protest, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
- Daily, Bishop Thomas: Clinic Demonstrations, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
- Datebooks, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
- Democratic National Convention Clinic Defense, 1992 (Box 1)
- Dinkins, Mayor David, 1989 (Box 1)
- Direct Action Training, 1988 (Box 1)
- Domino's Pizza Boycott, 1988-1991 (Box 1)
- Dump D'Amato, 1992 (Box 1)
- Fake Clinics, 1990-1992, 1994 (Box 1)
- Finances, 1990-1992 (Box 1)
- Finances: Reports, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
- Fliers and Palmcards, 1990-1994 (Box 1)
- Freedom of Choice Act, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
- Fundraising: Benefits and Events, 1989-1993 (Box 1)
- Fundraising: Direct Mail Appeals, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
- Fundraising: Grant proposals and reports, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
- Haitian Refugees, 1990, 1992 (Box 1)
- Grant Proposals and Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
- Herbally Aroused Gynecological Squad (HAGS) Working Group, 1989, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
- Holland Tunnel Civil Disobedience, 1992 (Box 1)
- Holland Tunnel Civil Disobedience: Legal Files, 1992 (Box 1)
- Informational Materials, undated (Box 1)
- Jones, Sabrina: Illustrations and WHAM Coloring Book, undated (Box 1)
- Lesbian Health Issues, undated (Box 1)
- March for Women's Lives, Washington, D.C., 1992 (Box 1)
- Media Working Group, 1993 (Box 1)
- Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1989-1992 (Box 2)
- Meixell, Elizabeth, 1994 (Box 2)
- Merchandise, 1994 (Box 2)
- Metropolitan New York Life Chain Counter Demonstration, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
- National Conference of Catholic Bishops: Hill & Knowlton Public Relations, 1990 (Box 2)
- National Health Care, 1991-1993 (Box 2)
- Net Worker, 1992 (Box 2)
- Networking Working Group, 1993 (Box 2)
- New Members Packet, 1991 (Box 2)
- New York City Board of Education, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
- New York City Council Budget Hearings, 1991 (Box 2)
- New York Clinic Defense Task Force, undated (Box 2)
- New York Clinic Defense Task Force, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
- New York Clinic Defense Task Force, 1993 (Box 2)
- New York Clinic Defense Task Force, 1994 (Box 2)
- New York Clinic Defense Task Force: Finances, 1992-1994 (Box 2)
- New York Clinic Defense Task Force: Meeting Agendas and Calendars, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
- Not-for-Profit Status, undated (Box 2)
- Notes: Elizabeth Meixell, 1990 (Box 2)
- October Outrage, 1991 (Box 2)
- O'Connor, John Cardinal Protests, 1987, 1990-1993 (Box 2)
- Operation Goliath: Dobbs Ferry Clinic Defense, 1990-1991, 1993 (Box 2)
- Operation Rescue/ "BORN" Blockades: WHAM Counter Demonstrations, 1989-1992 (Box 2)
- Operation Rescue's Capitol Project Protests, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
- Organizational Procedures and Forms, 1989-1992 (Box 2)
- Parental Leave Bill, undated (Box 2)
- Phone Zaps, 1990, 1992 (Box 2)
- Police Policy for Women's Medical Facilities, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
- Press Releases, 1990-1993 (Box 2)
- Proposed Standards of Care for Longterm Care Facilities For People with AIDS, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
- Reproductive Health: Self-Help, 1972, 1981, 1991, 1994 (Box 2)
- Reproductive Rights Coalition, 1989-1991 (Box 2)
- Resisting Racism Working Group, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
- RU-486 Working Group, 1989-1992 (Box 2)
- Saint Patrick's Cathedral Protests, 1989-1991 (Box 2)
- Saint Patrick's Cathedral Protests: Legal Files, 1990, 1994 (Box 2)
- Slogans: Proposed, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
- Souter Senate Judiciary Committee Hearings, 1990-1991, 1993 (Box 2)
- Souter Senate Judiciary Committee Hearings: Leal Files, 1990 (Box 2)
- Souter Senate Judiciary Committee Hearings: Statements and Questionnaires, 1990 (Box 2)
- Speaking Engagements, 1992 (Box 2)
- Statue of Liberty Action, 1991 (Box 2)
- Storage Inventory, 1993 (Box 2)
- Sununu, John, 1991 (Box 2)
- Supreme Court: Planned Parenthood v. Casey, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
- Supreme Court: Webster v. Reproductive Health Services Protests, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
- Surveillance, undated (Box 2)
- Susan B. Anthony Awards, 1990 (Box 2)
- Tax the Church, 1990 (Box 2)
- Terry, Randall, 1989-1993 (Box 2)
- Title X (Gag Rule) Protests, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
- Town Meetings, 1991-1993 (Box 2)
- United Nations: Appeal for Aid, 1991 (Box 2)
- United States Department of Health and Human Services Demonstration, 1990 (Box 2)
- Urban Herbalist, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
- Weekly Calendars and Contact Sheets, 1989-1994 (Box 3)
- WHAM Frontlines, 1990-1993 (Box 3)
- WHAM History, undated (Box 3)
- WHAM Members: Other Activities and Interests, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
- WHAM: Other Chapters, 1990, 1996 (Box 3)
- WHAM-Y Awards, undated (Box 3)
- Abortion: Access, 1989-1991 (Box 3)
- Abortion Clinic Bombings, 1987, 1990 (Box 3)
- Abortion: Elected Officials, 1989-1991 (Box 3)
- Abortion: Media Representation, 1989-1991 (Box 3)
- Abortion: History, 1990, 1992 (Box 3)
- Abortion: Religion, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
- ACT UP Women's Caucus: Women and AIDS Handbook, 1989 (Box 3)
- Adoption, 1989-1991 (Box 3)
- AIDS Drug Trials, Testing, and Treatment Glossary, 1988 (Box 3)
- American Bar Association: Abortion Stance, 1990 (Box 3)
- Anti-Abortion Activists, 1990-1993 (Box 3)
- Anti-Abortion Literature, 1990 (Box 3)
- AT&T: Abortion Stance, 1990 (Box 3)
- Boycott Handbook: Manuscript, 1991 (Box 3)
- Breast Implants, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
- Cervical Cancer, 1992 (Box 3)
- Challenging the Christian Right: The Activist's Handbook, 1992 (Box 3)
- Child Care, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
- Condom Distribution, 1991 (Box 3)
- Contraception, 1988, 1990-19993 (Box 3)
- Council of the City of New York: Access to Reproductive Services Act, 1994 (Box 3)
- Cuomo, Mario, 1990 (Box 3)
- Domestic Violence, 1983, 1990-1993 (Box 3)
- Fetal Rights: Clippings and Reports, 1986-1987, 1989 (Box 3)
- Fetal Rights: Clippings and Reports, 1990 (Box 3)
- Fetal Rights: Case Law Files (People of the State of California v. Pamela Rae Stewart), 1987-1989 (Box 3)
- Fetal Rights: Case Law Files, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
- Guam Abortion Law: Janet Benshoof Case, 1990 (Box 3)
- Helms, Jesse, 1990 (Box 3)
- HIV/AIDS: Women, 1988, 1990-1994 (Box 3)
- HIV/AIDS: Youth, 1990 (Box 3)
- Hodgson v. State of Minnesota, 1989 (Box 3)
- Holtzman, Elizabeth, 1988-1990 (Box 3)
- Idaho Abortion Law, 1990 (Box 3)
- International Women's Health Issues, 1990-1993 (Box 3)
- Lambs of Christ, undated (Box 3)
- Lesbian Issues, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
- Louisiana Abortion Bill, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
- Maternal and Child Health: New York City, 1987, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
- Operation Rescue: Wichita Protests, 1991 (Box 3)
- Parental/Judicial Consent, 1990-1992 (Box 3)
- Rafsky, Robert, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
- Rape, 19,911,993 (Box 3)
- Religious Right, undated (Box 3)
- Reproductive Rights: Art and video projects, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
- Safer Sex, undated (Box 3)
- St. John's Rape Trial, 1991 (Box 3)
- Target City Hall: An AIDS Activist's Guide to New York City, 1989 (Box 3)
- Terry, Randall: Injunction, 1989-1993 (Box 3)
- United States Supreme Court: Rust v. Sullivan, 1991 (Box 3)
- Women of Color: Health Issues, 1993 (Box 3)
- Clippings: General, undated (Box 4)
- Clippings: General, 1985, 1987-1989 (Box 4)
- Clippings: General, 1990 (Box 4)
- Clippings: General, 1990 (Box 4)
- Clippings: General, 1991 (Box 4)
- Clippings: General, 1992 (Box 4)
- Clippings: General, 1993 (Box 4)
- Clippings: General, 1994 (Box 4)
- Clippings: WHAM, 1989-1993 (Box 4)
- ACT UP (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power), undated (Box 4)
- ACT UP (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power), 1989 (Box 4)
- ACT UP (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power), 1990 (Box 4)
- ACT UP (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power), 1991 (Box 4)
- ACT UP (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power), 1992 (Box 4)
- ACT UP (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power), 1993-1994 (Box 4)
- American Civil Liberties Union: Reproductive Rights, 1990-1994 (Box 4)
- Update, undated (Box 4)
- Anti-Abortion Organizations, 1989-1994 (Box 4)
- Atlanta Pro-Choice Action Committee, undated (Box 4)
- Bard College Student Action Collaborative, 1990 (Box 4)
- Bay Area Coalition Against Operation Rescue, 1990, 1993 (Box 4)
- Bi-State Operation Rescue Network (BORN), 1990-1992 (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Pro-Choice Network, 1989-1991 (Box 4)
- Center for Reproductive Law and Policy, 1993 (Box 4)
- Center for Reproductive Law and Policy: Reproductive, 1992-1994 (Box 4)
- Freedom News, undated (Box 4)
- Clinic Defense Organizations, 1990 (Box 4)
- Escorter, 1993 (Box 4)
- Feminist Majority Foundation, undated (Box 4)
- Feminist Organizations: College Campuses, 1990 (Box 4)
- Feminists for Life, undated (Box 4)
- Helpers of God's Precious Infants, 1990-1991, 1993 (Box 4)
- HIV/AIDS organizations, undated (Box 4)
- Lesbian Avengers, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
- Lesbian Health Project: City of New York Department of Health, 1992 (Box 4)
- Manhattan Borough President's Reproductive Rights Task Force, 1990-1993 (Box 4)
- Men's Reproductive Rights Organizations, undated (Box 4)
- Mobilization for Women's Lives, 1989 (Box 4)
- National Abortion Clinic Defense Conference, 1990 (Box 4)
- National Abortion Federation, 1990 (Box 4)
- National Abortion Rights Action League, 1990, 1993 (Box 4)
- National Abortion Rights Action League: New York State (NYS-NARAL), 1990-1994 (Box 4)
- National Center for the Pro Choice Majority, 1993 (Box 4)
- National Organization for Women, 1990-1992 (Box 4)
- National Organization for Women: Naussau Chapter, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
- National Organization for Women: New York City Chapter, 1989-1992 (Box 4)
- National Organization for Women: Project Stand Up for Women Now, 1990 (Box 4)
- National Women's Rights Organizing Coalition, 1990-1992 (Box 4)
- New York Pro-Choice Coalition, undated (Box 4)
- Operation Rescue, 1990-1993 (Box 4)
- Operation Rescue: Restraining Orders, 1990, 1992 (Box 4)
- Planned Parenthood, 1989-1990 (Box 4)
- Pro-Choice Network, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
- Pro-Choice Organizations: National, 1992 (Box 4)
- Pro-Choice Organizations: New York Region, 1983, 1989-1990, 1994 (Box 4)
- Pro-Choice Organizations: Other areas, 1990 (Box 4)
- Radical Women's Groups, 1991 (Box 4)
- Refuse and Resist, 1989-1991, 1993 (Box 4)
- Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights, 1990 (Box 4)
- Reprovision, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
- Sister Serpents, 1990 (Box 4)
- Society to Outlaw Planned Parenthood (STOPP), 1990, 1992 (Box 4)
- Stand Up for Choice Video Project, undated (Box 4)
- Treatment Action Guerillas, 1991 (Box 4)
- Washington Area Clinic Defense Task Force, 1990-1993 (Box 4)